Guide to the Millicent Todd Bingham Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Education and Teaching, 1885-1929; Series III; 7.5 linear feet (18 boxes)
  - Harvard University
    - Geography
      - Maps, outlines, 1916 (Box 63, Folder 146)
      - Lecture notes, South America, 1916-1917 (Box 63, Folder 147)
      - Laboratory exercises, 1916 (Box 63, Folder 148)
    - Geology/geography notes, 1919-1920 (Box 63, Folder 149)
    - Geology
      - Basic concepts, notes of lectures by William Morris Davis, undated (Box 64, Folder 150)
      - Notes, 1916 (Box 64, Folder 151)
      - Maps of North America, undated (Box 64, Folder 152)
    - History of science notes, 1916 (Box 64, Folder 153)
    - Meteorology notebook and notes, 1916-1917 (Box 64, Folder 154-155)
    - Primitive sociology lecture notes, 1916-1917 (Box 64, Folder 156-157)
    - Memoranda, printed matter, 1922 (Box 64, Folder 158)
  - University of Grenoble
    - Geography: work on the geography of France, 1918-1919 (Box 64, Folder 159)
    - "Morphologie Glaciaire," notes, 1918-1919 (Box 64, Folder 160)
    - "Structure of North America," lecture notes, 1918-1919 (Box 64, Folder 161)
  - Teaching
    - Correspondence: job offers, 1902-1929 (Box 65, Folder 162)
    - Vassar College
      - Administrative correspondence, 1902-1904 (Box 65, Folder 163)
      - Teaching material, 1902-1904 (Box 65, Folder 164)
      - French teaching materials, 1903-1904 (Box 65, Folder 165-166)
      - Printed matter, 1903-1904 (Box 65, Folder 167)
    - Wellesley College
      - Correspondence, 1906-1907 (Box 65, Folder 168)
      - Class plans, 1906-1907 (Box 65, Folder 169-170)
      - Teaching materials, 1906-1907 (Box 65, Folder 171)
      - Themes, 1906-1907 (Box 65, Folder 172)
      - Notes and cards from friends, 1906-1907 (Box 65, Folder 173)
      - Personal expenses, 1906-1907 (Box 65, Folder 174)
      - College directories, 1906-1908 (Box 65, Folder 175)
      - College calendars, 1905-1908 (Box 66, Folder 176-177)
      - Program, 1907 (Box 66, Folder 178)
      - College newspapers, 1906-1907 (Box 66, Folder 179)
      - Magazine, 1911 (Box 66)
    - University of Grenoble
      - "Geography of France"
        - Syllabus, 1919 (Box 66, Folder 180)
        - Lecture notes, 1919 (Box 66, Folder 181)
    - Columbia University
      - Correspondence, 1928-1929 (Box 66, Folder 182)
      - Urban Geography
        - Course notes, 1928-1929 (Box 66, Folder 183-184)
        - Lecture notes, 1928-1929 (Box 66, Folder 185-186)
        - Examination papers, 1928-1929 (Box 67, Folder 187)
    - Sarah Lawrence College
      - Correspondence, 1927-1929 (Box 67, Folder 188)
      - Geography lecture notes, 1929 (Box 67, Folder 189)
      - Geography lecture outline and notes, 1929 (Box 67, Folder 190)
      - Printed matter, 1926-1929 (Box 67, Folder 191)
- Geography, 1898-1967; Series IV; 3 linear feet (8 boxes)
  Correspondence and Writings are arranged chronologically. Professional Organizations is arranged by organization. Printed Matter is arranged alphabetically by author, with shorter items arranged by type of material.
  - Correspondence
    - 1911-1968, no date (Box 68, Folder 1-16)
  - Writings
    - Peru, a Land of Contrasts
      - Published volume (Box 69, Folder 17)
      - Contract, 1913 September 20 (Box 69, Folder 18)
      - Early draft (Box 69, Folder 19-20)
      - Late draft (Box 69, Folder 21-23)
      - Designs and illustrations (Box 69, Folder 24)
      - Maps (Box 69, Folder 25)
      - Foreword (not used) (Box 69, Folder 26)
      - Advertising brochures (Box 69, Folder 27)
      - Reviews (Box 69, Folder 28)
    - R. Blanchard, Geography of France (translated by MT), 1919
      - Published edition (Box 69, Folder 29)
      - Financial papers (Box 69, Folder 30)
      - Publicity (Box 69, Folder 31)
      - Contract, 1919 July 31 (Box 70, Folder 32)
      - Manuscript draft (Box 70, Folder 33)
      - Article by Raoul Blanchard (Box 70, Folder 34)
      - Advertising brochures (Box 70, Folder 35)
    - Synopsis of R. Blanchard, A Study in Urban Geography, 1919
      - TMs (Box 70, Folder 36)
      - Articles in The Alpine Review, 1919 May (Box 70, Folder 37)
    - "The French School of Geography" (unpublished): TMs, 1919 (Box 70, Folder 38)
    - "An Investigation of Geographic Controls in Peru", 1923
      - TMs (Box 70, Folder 39)
      - Plans (Box 70, Folder 40)
      - Summary of thesis (Box 70, Folder 41)
      - Early draft (Box 70, Folder 42-45)
      - Early draft (Box 71, Folder 46-50)
      - Maps (Box 71, Folder 51-52)
      - Notes (Box 71, Folder 53)
      - Reference material (Box 71, Folder 54-55)
    - "Le Relief du Peru": printed copy, reprints of article, 1925 (Box 71, Folder 56-57)
    - Vidal de la Blache, Principles of Human Geography (translated by MTB ), 1926
      - Translation notes (Box 71, Folder 58)
      - Reviews (Box 71, Folder 59)
    - Articles in Social Science Abstracts, 1929 July
      - Printed edition (Box 71, Folder 60)
      - Manuscript (Box 71, Folder 61)
    - Articles for Encyclopedia Britannica, 1929
      - Early draft (Box 71, Folder 62-64)
      - Late draft (Box 72, Folder 65)
      - Maps (Box 72, Folder 66)
      - Printed matter (pamphlets) (Box 72, Folder 67)
      - Notes (Box 72, Folder 68)
    - "A Method of Approach to Urban Geography", 1930 October
      - Printed copy ( Bulletin of the Geographical Society of Philadelphia ) (Box 72, Folder 69)
      - TMs (Box 72, Folder 70)
    - "Geographers in Paris": printed copy ( Vassar Quarterly ), 1931 November (Box 72, Folder 71)
    - "Vocational Geography," review of Wallace W. Atwood, The World at Work (Personnel Journal), 1932 April (Box 72, Folder 72)
    - "Ellen Churchill Semple, Geographer" ( Vassar Quarterly ), 1932 July (Box 72, Folder 73)
    - "La Floride du Sud-est et la Ville de Miami", 1932
      - TMs of speech to International Congress of Geography, 1931 (Box 72, Folder 74)
      - Mélanges Géographiques (article reprints), 1932 (Box 72, Folder 75)
      - Revue de Géographie Alpine (printed copy), 1933 (Box 72, Folder 76)
    - "Miami, a Study in Urban Geography", 1948
      - Printed article (Box 72, Folder 77)
      - TMs in English (Box 72, Folder 78)
      - Manuscript in French (Box 72, Folder 79)
    - "The City of Miami and Southeastern Florida", 1949
      - TMs (Box 73, Folder 80)
      - Research articles (Box 73, Folder 81-82)
      - Maps (Box 73, Folder 83)
      - Notes (Box 73, Folder 84)
  - Professional Organizations
    - Congrès International de Géographie, 1931 September
      - Resumés des Communications (Box 73, Folder 85)
      - Maps (Box 73, Folder 86-87)
      - Notes (Box 73, Folder 88)
      - Printed matter (Box 73, Folder 89-90)
      - Memorabilia (Box 73, Folder 91)
    - The Society of Women Geographers: printed matter, correspondence, 1928-1963 (Box 73, Folder 92)
    - Association of American Geographers
      - Printed matter, correspondence, 1916-1945 (Box 73, Folder 93)
      - 1926 convention, printed program and notes (Box 73, Folder 94)
    - American Geographical Society: printed matter, 1915-1967 (Box 73, Folder 95)
    - The Geological Society of America: printed matter, 1953-1954 (Box 73, Folder 96)
  - Printed Matter
    - Dorsey, A Bibliography of the Anthropology of Peru, 1898 (Box 74, Folder 97)
    - Article reprints: Bulletin of the American Geographical Society, 1910-1913 (Box 74, Folder 98)
    - R. Blanchard, Grenoble, 1912 (Box 74, Folder 99)
    - The Geographical Review, 1919 (Box 74, Folder 100)
    - Germán Stiglich, Diccionario Geográfico del Perú (3v.), 1922 (Box 74, Folder 101-103)
    - O. M. Quesada, Elementos de Geografía Científica del Perú, 1925 (Box 74, Folder 104)
    - A. B. Leguia, Republica del Peru, Mensaje, 1927 (Box 74, Folder 105)
    - A. J. Hanna, Recommended Readings on Florida, 1945 (Box 74, Folder 106)
    - Pamphlets, 1899-1948, undated (Box 75, Folder 107-117)
    - Invitations and programs, 1919-1949 (Box 75, Folder 118)
    - Newspaper clippings, undated (Box 75, Folder 119)
- Emily Dickinson, 1828-(1894-1956)-1969; Series V; 16 linear feet (39 boxes)
  Research Correspondence and Publication Correspondence are arranged chronologically. Select Correspondence is arranged alphabetically.
  Books, Articles and Speeches is arranged chronologically by publication date. Publication Documents and Notes is organized by type of material and chronologically under each heading. Source Documents and Research Notes is organized in three parts: 1) sources, by subject; 2) notes, chronologically by publication date of MTB's books and articles; 3) Jay Leyda's notes, alphabetically by subject.
  Scrapbooks and Articles by Others are arranged chronologically.
  For MTB's taped history of the Emily Dickinson materials see: APPENDIX, Records and Tapes, Items 6-7.
  - Research Correspondence
    - 1926-1960, no date (Box 76, Folder 1-11)
  - Publication Correspondence
    - 1898-1943 (Box 76, Folder 12-23)
    - 1944 Jan-1950 Aug (Box 77, Folder 24-55)
    - 1950 Sep-1952 Dec (Box 78, Folder 56-78)
    - 1953 Jan-1955 May (Box 79, Folder 79-110)
    - 1955 Jun-1958 Dec (Box 80, Folder 111-139)
    - 1959 Jan-1968 Nov (Box 80, Folder 140-162)
  - Select Correspondence
    - A (Box 81, Folder 163)
    - Aiken, Conrad, 1948 (Box 81, Folder 164)
    - Allen, Hervey, 1926-1945 (Box 81, Folder 165)
    - Anderson, Charles, 1957-1961 (Box 81, Folder 166)
    - Arnold, Helen H., 1945-1958 (Box 81, Folder 167)
    - Askling, John
      - 1946-1954 (Box 81, Folder 168-171)
      - 1955-1968 (Box 82, Folder 172-175)
    - Ba-Bl (Box 82, Folder 176)
    - Bo (Box 82, Folder 177)
    - Br (Box 82, Folder 178)
    - Bu (Box 82, Folder 179)
    - Bechtel, Edwin DeT., 1945 (Box 82, Folder 180)
    - Brenner, George A., 1966-1968 (Box 82, Folder 181)
    - Ca (Box 82, Folder 182)
    - Ch-Cl (Box 82, Folder 183)
    - Co-Cu (Box 82, Folder 184)
    - D (Box 82, Folder 185)
    - De Voto, Bernard, 1947 (Box 82, Folder 186)
      See also: box 2, folder 26
    - E-F (Box 82, Folder 187)
    - Ferris, Lincoln Stuart, 1965-1967 (Box 82, Folder 188)
    - Franklin, Ralph, 1962-1968 (Box 82, Folder 189-196)
    - Ga-Gl (Box 82, Folder 197)
    - Go (Box 82, Folder 198)
    - Gr (Box 82, Folder 199)
    - Graves, Louise B., 1930-1956, undated (Box 83, Folder 200-205)
    - Green, Charles R., 1930-1964 (Box 83, Folder 206-209)
    - Ha (Box 83, Folder 210)
    - He-Hi (Box 83, Folder 211)
    - Ho-Hu (Box 83, Folder 212)
    - Hersey, Frances, 1945-1960, undated (Box 83, Folder 213-217)
    - Higgins, David, 1959-1968 (Box 83, Folder 218-223)
    - Hillyer, Robert S., 1931-1959 (Box 83, Folder 224)
    - Hubbard, Elizabeth Wright, 1952-1955 (Box 83, Folder 225)
    - I-J (Box 83, Folder 226)
    - Johnson, Thomas H., 1950-1956 (Box 83, Folder 227-231)
    - K (Box 84, Folder 232)
    - Keep, Wallace, 1933 (Box 84, Folder 233)
    - L (Box 84, Folder 234)
    - Leary, Lewis, 1950-1967 (Box 84, Folder 235)
    - Leyda, Jay, 1951-1967 (Box 84, Folder 236-242)
    - Ma (Box 84, Folder 243)
    - Mac (Box 84, Folder 244)
    - Me-Mi (Box 84, Folder 245)
    - Mo-Mu (Box 84, Folder 246)
    - Morey, Frederick L., 1965-1969 (Box 84, Folder 247)
    - N-O (Box 84, Folder 248)
    - P (Box 84, Folder 249)
    - Parke, Ethel, 1947-1955 (Box 84, Folder 250)
    - ________, Priscilla (Box 84)
    - Patterson, Rebecca, 1947-1962, undated (Box 84, Folder 251-258)
    - Pearl, Clara Carleton, 1932-1953 (Box 84, Folder 258a)
    - Pollack, Queena, 1932-1956 (Box 85, Folder 259)
    - R (Box 85, Folder 260)
    - Raney, M. L., 1954-1964, undated (Box 85, Folder 261-264)
    - Sa-Sm (Box 85, Folder 265)
    - Sp-Sw (Box 85, Folder 266)
    - Schappes, Morris U., 1932-1933 (Box 85, Folder 267)
    - Sewall, Richard, 1946-1968 (Box 85, Folder 268-285)
    - Shackford, Martha Hale, 1943-1960 (Box 86, Folder 286-288)
    - Smidt, Aagot Karner, 1960-1967 (Box 86, Folder 289)
    - Smith, Russel St. Clair, 1945-1955 (Box 86, Folder 290-291)
    - T (Box 86, Folder 292)
    - Untermeyer, Louis, 1931-1962, undated (Box 86, Folder 293-295)
    - Van Doren, Mark, 1944-1962 (Box 86, Folder 296)
      See also:box 10, folder 168
    - W (Box 86, Folder 297)
    - Ward, Theodora V. W., 1932-1961, undated (Box 86, Folder 298-299)
    - Wells, Carlton F., 1956-1968 (Box 86, Folder 300-301)
    - Wells, Henry W., 1946-1967 (Box 86, Folder 302)
    - Whicher, George F., 1931-1962 (Box 86, Folder 303)
    - ________, Harriet (Box 86)
  - Books, Articles and Speeches
    - Letters of Emily Dickinson: first edition with added illustrations, 1894
      - Volume 1 (Box 86, Folder 304)
      - Volume 2 (Box 87, Folder 305)
    - 1931
      - Typescript of new passages (Box 87, Folder 306)
      - Drafts of preface and introduction; list of illustrations (Box 87, Folder 307)
      - Material not used, and duplicates (Box 87, Folder 308)
    - "Emily Dickinson": notes and manuscript, 1932 May 18 (Box 87, Folder 309)
    - "Emily Dickinson's Earliest Friend," in, 1934 May (Box 87, Folder 310)
    - "New Light on Emily Dickinson", 1943
      - Final draft (Box 87, Folder 311)
      - Preliminary draft (Box 87, Folder 312)
      - First draft and notes (Box 87, Folder 313)
      - Later revisions (Box 87, Folder 314)
    - Bolts of Melody, 1945
      - Galleys (Box 87, Folder 315)
      - Drafts of introduction (Box 87, Folder 316)
      - Index of first lines (Box 88, Folder 317)
      - Poems, A-Z (Box 88, Folder 318-323)
    - Ancestors' Brocades, 1945
      - Page proofs (Box 88, Folder 324)
      - Final draft
        - Author's Note, Prologue, Chapters 1-4 (Box 88, Folder 325)
        - Chapters 5-21 (Box 89, Folder 326-328)
      - Late corrections (Box 89, Folder 329)
      - Early draft: Preface, Chapters 1-10, Postlude (Box 89, Folder 330-333)
      - First draft (Box 89, Folder 334)
      - First draft with Mabel Loomis Todd's comments (Box 90, Folder 335)
      - Comments by others on early drafts (Box 90, Folder 336)
    - Emily Dickinson Exhibition at Grolier Club, 1945 (Box 90, Folder 337)
    - "Poems of Emily Dickinson: Hitherto Published Only in Part", 1947 March
      - Published article, in New England Quarterly (Box 90, Folder 338)
      - Manuscript draft (Box 90, Folder 339)
    - "Emily Dickinson's Handwriting - a Master Key": drafts and published article (in New England Quarterly ), 1949 June (Box 90, Folder 340)
    - Emily Dickinson - A Revelation: incomplete early draft, 1954 (Box 90, Folder 341)
    - Emily Dickinson's Home, 1945
      - Late draft (Box 90, Folder 342-345)
      - Late draft (Box 91, Folder 346-348)
      - Early draft (Box 91, Folder 349-354)
      - Unpublished chapter on lawsuit (Part 1) (Box 91, Folder 355)
      - Unpublished chapter on lawsuit (Part 2) (Box 92, Folder 356)
      - "Note on Editing Emily Dickinson" (Box 92, Folder 357)
      - "Edward Dickinson in Congress," by Willoughby Todd (Box 92, Folder 358)
      - "Edward Dickinson in Congress," condensed by MTB (Box 92, Folder 359-360)
      - Drafts of preface (Box 92, Folder 361)
      - Drafts of "Relatives, Friends and Relations" (Box 92, Folder 362)
      - Passages substituted at Harper's (Box 92, Folder 363)
      - Publisher's material (Box 92, Folder 364)
    - "Prose Fragments of Emily Dickinson": drafts and published article ( New England Quarterly ), 1955 September (Box 92, Folder 365)
    - The Dickinson Collection": drafts, 1955 (Box 92, Folder 366)
    - "Guide to the Use of the Microfilm of the Emily Dickinson Manuscripts": drafts and mimeographed article, 1957 October (Box 92, Folder 367)
    - "A Moment of Drama": drafts and published article ( Radcliffe Quarterly ), 1959 February (Box 92, Folder 368)
    - "The First Editing of Emily Dickinson": early and final drafts, 1965 (Box 92, Folder 369)
    - "Tape Recording of ED's Poems": draft of introduction, undated (Box 92, Folder 370)
  - Publication Documents and Notes
    - Documents
      - Agreements with publishers, 1931-1966 (Box 93, Folder 371)
      - Harvard-Harper's controversy, 1887-1961 (Box 93, Folder 372)
      - Donation of Dickinson papers, 1956-1957 (Box 93, Folder 373)
    - MTB notes
      - 1928-1955 (Box 93, Folder 374-390)
      - 1956-1968 (Box 94, Folder 391-408)
      - no date (Box 94, Folder 409-417)
    - Alexander S. Andrews notes, 1931-1954, undated (Box 95, Folder 418-420)
    - Publicity for publications, 1894-1967 (Box 95, Folder 421-422)
    - Publicity for donation of papers, 1956-1958 (Box 95, Folder 423)
    - Printed matter re: copyright laws, 1925-1958 (Box 95, Folder 424)
  - Source Documents and Research Notes
    - Emily Dickinson poems
      - "Manuscripts of Emily Dickinson Poems," list of poems in MTB collection, 1954 (Box 95, Folder 425)
      - Lists of poems and letters by ED, undated (Box 95, Folder 426)
      - Fascicle 80 - Fascicle 94 (Box 95, Folder 427-441)
      - Fascicle 95 - Fascicle 110 (Box 96, Folder 442-460)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 96, Folder 461-462)
      - Duplicates (Box 96, Folder 463-464)
      - Envelopes and notes by MLT and MTB (Box 96, Folder 465)
      - Cataloguing notes, poems #96-891 (Box 97, Folder 466-473)
    - Emily Dickinson letters (photostatic copies)
      - To Mr. and Mrs. Samuel Bowles (Box 97, Folder 474-479)
      - To Professor Chickering (Box 97, Folder 480)
      - To James D. Clark (Box 97, Folder 481-484)
      - To Lavinia Dickinson (Box 97, Folder 485)
      - To William Austin Dickinson (Box 97, Folder 486)
      - To William Austin Dickinson (Box 98, Folder 487)
      - To John L. Graves (Box 98, Folder 488)
      - To Dr. and Mrs. Holland (Box 98, Folder 489)
      - To Helen Hunt Jackson (Box 98, Folder 490)
      - To Mr. and Mrs. Eben Jenks Loomis (Box 98, Folder 491)
      - To Judge Otis P. Lord (Box 98, Folder 492-493)
      - To "Master" (Box 98, Folder 494)
      - To Mabel Loomis Todd (Box 98, Folder 495)
      - To Mrs. Ward (Box 98, Folder 496)
      - To various correspondents (Box 98, Folder 497)
      - To unknown correspondents (Box 98, Folder 498-499)
    - Emily Dickinson prose fragments (Box 98, Folder 500-503)
    - Dickinson family correspondence
      - 1851-1853 (Box 98, Folder 504-508)
      - 1853-1854 (Box 99, Folder 509-511)
      - Edward Dickinson and William Austin Dickinson, 1874 (Box 99, Folder 512-513)
      - Miscellaneous letters (photographs) (Box 99, Folder 514)
      - Miscellaneous letters (negatives) (Box 99, Folder 515)
      - Duplicate letters (Box 99, Folder 516)
    - Edward Dickinson letters to Graves family (Box 99, Folder 517)
    - Lavinia Dickinson to "Gertrude" (Box 99, Folder 518)
    - Letters from Charles Wadsworth (photographs and negatives) (Box 99, Folder 519)
    - Austin Keep letters to Mabel Loomis Todd (Box 99, Folder 520)
    - Illustrations for MTB books (Box 99, Folder 521)
    - Biographical material about Judge Lord (Box 99, Folder 522)
    - Fictionalized version of Bianchi affair (Box 99, Folder 523)
    - Letters of Emily Dickinson: research notes, 1931 (Box 99, Folder 524-526)
    - Bolts of Melody, 1945
      - ED poems published by Bianchi in 1935, A-Z (Box 99, Folder 527-528)
      - MTB's original lists of poems, 1944 (Box 99, Folder 529)
      - Research notes (Box 99, Folder 530-533)
      - Research notes (Box 100, Folder 534)
    - Ancestors' Brocades, 1945
      - Correspondence re: first publication of Emily Dickinson
        - 1883-1895 (Box 100, Folder 535-537)
        - "Firuski letters", 1890-1896 (Box 100, Folder 538)
        - "Galatea copies", 1890-1893 (Box 100, Folder 539)
      - Correspondence re: preparation of Emily Dickinson letters, 1891-1894 (Box 100, Folder 540)
      - Excerpts from Mabel Loomis Todd's diary, 1881-1886 (Box 100, Folder 541)
      - Research notes (Box 100, Folder 542-550)
    - "Poems of Emily Dickinson: Hitherto Published Only in Part": research notes, 1947 March (Box 100, Folder 551)
    - "Emily Dickinson's Handwriting": research notes, 1949 (Box 100, Folder 552)
    - Emily Dickinson - A Revelation: research notes, 1954 (Box 100, Folder 553-555)
    - Emily Dickinson's Home, 1955
      - Biographies by others (Box 100, Folder 556)
      - Death certificates (Box 100, Folder 557)
      - Deeds and lawsuits (Box 100, Folder 558)
      - Samuel Fowler Dickinson, biographical material and "Oration" (Box 101, Folder 559)
      - Excerpts from diary of Mrs. William Flynt, 1848-1865 (Box 101, Folder 560)
      - Excerpts from diary of Emily Fowler Ford, 1839-1891 (Box 101, Folder 561)
      - John L. Graves, biographical material (Box 101, Folder 562)
      - Excerpts from diary of Sarah Phelps Hadley, 1856-1865 (Box 101, Folder 563)
      - Massachusetts House of Representatives, documents, 1874 (Box 101, Folder 564)
      - Reminiscences of Emily Dickinson (Box 101, Folder 565)
      - Obituaries of Emily and Lavinia Dickinson (Box 101, Folder 566)
      - Scrapbook of Elizabeth Dickinson Currier, 1870-1895 (Box 101, Folder 567)
      - Scrapbook of Annie Dickinson (Currier) Brown, 1873-1912 (Box 101, Folder 568)
      - Sweetser family correspondence, 1833-1868 (Box 102, Folder 569-570)
      - Wills (Box 102, Folder 571)
      - Research notes (Box 102, Folder 572-590)
      - Research notes (Box 103, Folder 591-599)
    - "Prose Fragments of Emily Dickinson": research notes, 1955 (Box 103, Folder 600-601)
    - Miscellaneous research notes
      - MTB conversations with her mother, 1930-1932 (Box 103, Folder 602)
      - Projected anthology of ED, 1955-1968 (Box 103, Folder 603-604)
      - 1955-1968 (Box 103, Folder 605)
      - no date (Box 103, Folder 606-608)
      - no date (Box 104, Folder 609-610)
    - Jay Leyda notes
      - "Years and Hours - Austin" (Box 104, Folder 611)
      - "Amherst Academy" (Box 104, Folder 612)
      - "Church" (Box 104, Folder 613)
      - "Amherst town records" (Box 104, Folder 614)
      - "Accounts - local stores" (Box 104, Folder 615)
      - "Kate Anthon" (Box 104, Folder 616)
      - "Beecher diary" (Box 104, Folder 617)
      - "Boltwood diaries" (Box 104, Folder 618)
      - "Eudocia Coleman Converse Flynt" (Box 104, Folder 619)
      - "Rev. Austin Dickinson" (Box 104, Folder 620)
      - "Library - in D. home" (Box 104, Folder 621)
      - "Music (list of all pieces in D. house)" (Box 104, Folder 622)
      - "Sermons" (Box 104, Folder 623)
      - "Contemporary glimpses of ED" (Box 104, Folder 624)
      - "Beaman diary" (Box 104, Folder 625)
      - "E.D. girlhood letters" (Box 104, Folder 626)
      - "Jameson diaries" (Box 104, Folder 627)
      - "Lord Farley" (Box 104, Folder 628)
      - "Sermons by Sam. Mack" (Box 104, Folder 629)
      - "Norcross letters" (Box 104, Folder 630)
      - "Skinner, Leander" (Box 104, Folder 631)
      - "Sweetser" (Box 104, Folder 632)
      - "Seelye papers" (Box 104, Folder 633)
      - "Genevieve Taggard" (Box 104, Folder 634)
      - "Tyler letters ... and diary" (Box 104, Folder 635)
      - Newspapers (Box 104, Folder 636-638)
      - Newspapers (Box 105, Folder 639-640)
      - "1828" - "1864" (Box 105, Folder 641-651)
      - "1865" - "1886" (Box 106, Folder 652-660)
      - ED papers (photostatic copies) (Box 106, Folder 661-664)
      - Illustrations for The Years and Hours of Emily Dickinson (1960) (Box 106, Folder 665)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 106, Folder 666)
  - Scrapbooks
    - " Poems by E.D., First Series", 1890-1892 (Box 107, Folder 667)
    - " Poems by E.D., Second Series", 1891-1896 (Box 107, Folder 668)
    - "Letters of Emily Dickinson", 1894-1895 (Box 107, Folder 669)
    - Album, 1895-1945 (Box 108, Folder 670)
    - "Further Poems of E.D. (Bianchi); Books about E.D.", 1922-1930 (Box 108, Folder 671)
    - "Letters of E.D., New and enlarged edition; Articles, plays about E.D.", 1929-1931 (Box 109, Folder 672)